<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz</id>
    <title>Gingermilk&apos;s Cabin</title>
    <updated>2021-05-10T02:33:49.640Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>A place for me to record things.</subtitle>
    <logo>https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2021, Gingermilk&apos;s Cabin</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Alternative Interpretation of Kon Satoshi's Perfect Blue (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post/an-alternative-interpretation-of-kon-satoshis-perfect-blue-part-1/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post/an-alternative-interpretation-of-kon-satoshis-perfect-blue-part-1/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-05-08T14:06:20.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This post contains lots of pictures</em><br>
<em>I don't want my post to be too long so I decided to split it into two parts</em></p>
<hr>
<p><img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620612704545.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
Recently I rewatched <em>Perfect Blue</em>, a psychological film directed by Satoshi Kon published in 1997. If you know nothing about this film, it is basically a story centered around Mima Kirigoe, an idol who decided to quit and became an actress but developed multiple personality disorder during this process of transformation. Unless you don't mind getting spoilers or understanding absolutely nothing of what I am going to say next, I highly recommend you to watch the film before proceeding to read the rest of this post or at least reading <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perfect_Blue#Plot">the plot part of wikipedia</a>.</p>
<p><em>Perfect Blue</em> is a masterpiece of apparition, identity, consciousness, and horror, which at the same time ambiguates the theme and makes the entire film difficult to understand. Satoshi Kon's technique also perfectly accomplished the task of trapping his audiences into an overlapping realm of illusion and reality. Even after reaching the end, Satoshi Kon still refuses to give us a satisfying answer on whether or not Mima has her mind returned to reality as he decided to make that famous smile an opening ending question.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620612767692.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Many people have given out a variety of interpretation and analysis on this film with different focuses, while most of them share the following conception:</p>
<ul>
<li>Kirigoe Mima exists and is real.</li>
<li>Mimarin existed as a persona and is fake after Mima pursues the career of an actress.</li>
<li>Rumi exists and is real.</li>
<li>Me-Mania exists and is real.</li>
<li>Youko (Mima's character in <em>Double Bind</em>) does not exist and is fake.</li>
</ul>
<p>Although I have found some alternative opinions that have completely flipped the existing common conception, almost all of them are fragments of hypothesis with minimum evidence accompanied rather than a complete theory like the &quot;all-characters-exist-and-Rumi-is-the-bad-one&quot; theories you can find everywhere on the internet. There are two main theories in this category, one holds the point that everything is an illusion of Youko, and the other one holds the point that everything is an illusion of Rumi. The former one is plausible but I found it hard to connect all the pieces together, so I am more leaning toward the second one here.</p>
<p>As what you might have already guessed from the title, today I am going to complete (or at least trying to) this alternative theory by taking a relook at the plot and all the details while not going too deep into the analysis of psychology, philosophy, or symbology.</p>
<hr>
<p><em><strong>The Framework</strong></em></p>
<p>Only the third and fifth common conception applies to my explanation of this film. In this alternative interpretation, nothing &quot;exists&quot; and everything is &quot;fake&quot; except the final scene where Rumi is placed in a mental hospital. The entire film is merely a misty reproduction of Rumi's past modified by Rumi to ease the pain she has experienced from the collapse of her dream and career as an idol, unpleasant memory of being sexually harassed and raped, and the lack of a mentor that guides her on her way toward maturity. However, as Mima gains consciousness from acting in the drama, she manages to escape from Rumi's fantasy and directly interact with the reality. The modified version is as followed:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Kirigoe Mima didn't exist and was not real until the end of the film.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Mimarin doesn't exist and is not real.</strong></li>
<li>Rumi exists and is real.</li>
<li><strong>Me-Mania existed and was real.</strong></li>
<li>Youko does not exist and is fake.</li>
</ul>
<p>This film can be divided into three sections in my opinion: <strong>before the chaos</strong>, <em><strong>Double Bind</strong></em>, and <strong>after the chaos</strong>. &quot;Before the chaos&quot; indicates the beginning part of the movie where Mima still appears conscious of herself; &quot;<em>Double Bind</em>&quot; indicates the content of the drama Mima takes part in; and &quot;After the Chaos&quot; indicates the ending part of the movie where illusion and reality are mixed up and Mima keeps waking up.</p>
<p>In order to avoid confusion, I will call each persona/character by the following name:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Mima</em>: the one who decides to quit singing and become an actress and gets illusions of herself as an idol (the one that splits from Mimarin)</li>
<li><em>Mimarin</em>: the persona of Mima as an idol (real Rumis's reflection of younger self)</li>
<li><em>Rumi</em>: Mima's manager who always accompanies her (real Rumi's reflection of self)</li>
<li><em>real Rumi</em>: the one who is in the mental hospital, the entire film is a fantasy of hers based on her past</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><em><strong>Before the Chaos</strong></em></p>
<p>At the beginning of the movie (or to be more clear, the beginning of Rumi's fantasy), Mimarin, is doing her last performance with the group.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620612855735.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>The shot keeps switching among the performance of the girls, the conversation Rumi has with the other manager on Mima, and the creepy man Me-Mania. Real Rumi reflects her younger self on the persona of Mimarin and takes complete control upon her because she is able to directly copy all her memory as an idol and thoughts to her. Rumi, a persona that real Rumi has also complete control upon due to the same reason, serves as a mentor that is absent from real Rumi's past. For all other characters that appear in the film involving Mima who splits from Mimarin, real Rumi takes only part of the control as she does not directly represent any of them. Me-Mania is an exception due to real Rumi's reluctance to recall him from her past. He exists only in real Rumi's unconsciousness and materializes in her fantasy without real Rumi realizing until a certain point we will discuss later.</p>
<p>We are constantly seeing signs alluding the irrationality of this fake reality in the film. After the performance ends, Mima hears a mysterious man's voice saying &quot;I am always looking into Mima's room&quot;.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620612888040.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>When she arrives home, she receives a mysterious call that has no voice coming through but a man's heavy breath, a letter that says the same thing as the voice, and a mysterious fax that prints &quot;traitor&quot; over and over.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620612908782.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>These three incidents display an incoherence and remains unsolved even until the end of the film. The fax is arguable and it can be possibly from Rumi, but I think I could safely say that the voice, the call, the letter, and the fax are all part of real Rumi's unconsciousness that accuses her younger self of quitting the idol group.</p>
<p>The shot now switches to Mima practicing her lines for Youko. There is only one line for her: &quot;Who are you&quot;. As Mima repeats this line, her personality starts to mingle with Youko and thus diminishes her obedience to real Rumi. By questioning &quot;Who are you&quot; not only to the drama character but also to herself, Mima develops her own memories, personality, and mindset that is separate from those of real Rumi's.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620612930931.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Suddenly something explodes and Tadokoro (the manager) gets hurt. Mima hurries to where Tadokoro falls and picks up a piece of paper that has &quot;...is a warning. The next one will be real&quot; written on it.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620612948190.png" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620612960810.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>In my opinion, Real Rumi has manipulated Rumi to accomplish all the killings of people that once hurt her in the past, including this incident. It marks the beginning of real Rumi's revenge.</p>
<p>Mima purchases a new computer and asks Rumi to teach her. Here comes one of the most important component of the film: the website &quot;Mima's Room&quot;.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620613022228.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>There are many possible ways to interpret Mima's Room, but I believe that Mima's Room does not exist on the public internet and has no real author. It is a manifestation of real Rumi's mind while Mimarin serves as a protocol that regulates connection across the LAN, on which people can access the website. Through Mima's Room, everyone on the LAN can be interconnected and exchange information recorded on Mima's diary. So far only three people are shown in the film accessing the website: Mima, Rumi, and Me-Mania. All three of them have experienced illusions of Mimarin after or while reading the website so I stated that Mimarin is the protocol. Me-Mania doesn't share the full right to both read and modify the content because his own mind is still shackled in the unconscious section of real Rumi's mind yet Mima's Room is a representation of consciousness that real Rumi has dominant control upon. Me-Mania's presence on the LAN also partially explains why Mima hallucinates about Me-Mania before she is in physical contact with him. It is Mima's Room that bridges their mind.</p>
<p>I said that the website is not real because of some details that are so minor to a point you can just consider them irrelevant bugs the director is too busy to even take care of. If you take a really close look to the picture of Mima's Room above, you can see that the website has 12069 visitors. Now pay close attention to all times where Mima's Room appear and you will notice that the visitor number has been stuck at 12069. Take another look in that screenshot and you can see that the last update date is 96/05/07. However, the last diary entry Mima reads is from 05/12, the date she attends the drama production. They are two signs of incoherence that indicate the false existence of Mima's Room. As I said, they probably don't even matter but I am going to take every detail seriously like a real nerd. You can't stop me.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620613008032.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>After accessing Mima's Room, Mima has her first hallucination of Mimarin on her way to the drama production studio. This solidifies my theory on how Mima's Room interconnects people's minds and Mimarin serves as the protocol.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620613042130.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>The drama director has asked Mima to participate in a rape scene. Even though Rumi is strongly against this suggestion, Mima agrees. This is a critical point of Mima's transformation from Mimarin as an idol to Mima as an actress. Idols are symbols of purity yet Mima's acceptance of being involved in a rape scene deprives her of such quality, which also leads her to be taken nudes later in the film.</p>
<p>During the acting, Rumi has cried and got away from her seat as the scene becomes too aggressive and unbearable. I will talk more about this in the <em>Double Bind</em> section.</p>
<p>Mima goes home and tries to appear cheerful, but after seeing her fish died, she loses her mind and begins to cry. The illusion of Mimarin appears again on the computer screen, mocking Mima for being a whore. Suddenly the scene switches to the fish tank and even though the previous shot has shown that all fish are dead, there are two fishes happily swimming inside the tank and no dead fish is present. I would take this as a representation of the duality of real Rumi (Mimarin and Rumi) that warns Mima to obey to the persona of Mimarin. The disappearance of dead fish is yet another incoherence that real Rumi produces unconsciously.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620613065537.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Soon after the rape scene, the first death emerges. The script writer of the drama is found dead in the elevator with his eyes poked. Many believe that this murder is accomplished by Me-Mania because of the shot of Me-Mania reading Mima's Room, on which Mima complains about being forced to participate in the rape scene. In order to make my theory plausible, I would have to say that Rumi is the criminal behind all these murders. Real Rumi produces this fantasy to temporarily forget the trauma she once experienced and the murders are part of her revenge toward people who have caused her suffering. In order to reinforce the role of Rumi as the guardian, real Rumi designates her to do all those dirty stuff while maintaining the purity of Mimarin, who should have the most hatred toward people who are involved in tarnishing her.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620613174903.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Here comes my personal favorite part of the film. Mima accepts the offer to be taken photos for a magazine while the photographer is notorious for letting all his models strip. Meanwhile the rest of the idol group is performing on the stage while Me-Mania is among the audiences. The shots keep switching between the photographer taking nudes of Mima and the group performing on the stage, signifying the official death of Mima and also real Rumi's idol career as real Rumi has exactly the same experience as Mima. As the film progresses, Mima starts to hallucinate more about Mimarin. While she is resting after taking the photos, Mimarin appears at the door and opens the door while smiling. The shot switches to the stage, where Mimarin joins them and sings with them. The Mimarin on the stage is reflected by Me-Mania.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620613187112.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Me-Mania receives an email from Mima saying that the Mima he now sees is an imposter and asking him what she should do. He replies that he will get rid of her. The email is drafted by the conscious mind of real Rumi(so either Rumi or Mimarin sends the email) as she slowly notices Mima's psychological separation from Mimarin and the existence of Me-Mania in her fantasy. Despite her disdain of Me-Mania due to her unpleasant memory of him that we will talk about later, she has still decided to manipulate Me-Mania to execute Mima before she completely loses control of her behavior and thoughts.<br>
<img src="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post-images/1620613205931.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a simple proxy with V2ray]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post/building-a-simple-proxy-with-v2ray/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post/building-a-simple-proxy-with-v2ray/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-04-13T11:37:15.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>V2ray is &quot;a platform for building proxies to bypass network restrictions&quot;. You can find the github page <a href="https://github.com/v2fly/v2ray-core">here</a>, the official English website <a href="https://www.v2ray.com/en/index.html">here</a>, and also <a href="https://www.v2fly.org/en_US/">here</a>. As you might have noticed, v2ray is not a tool invented primarily for privacy (but it is very tweakable for all kinds of purposes), bur is rather used to bypass the GFW in China. Most of you will never use it probably, but it is always fun to try new things, am I right? And remember what I have said, its customization gives you a variety of options to play around with, like obfuscation, transparent proxy, or even ad blocking.</p>
<p>In a nutshell, v2ray uses a inbound-and-outbound structure to control the flow of packets. If v2ray is used on a client, then the inbound will receive data from the browser and the outbound will send data to the server; if v2ray is used on a server, then the inbound will receive data from the client and the outbound will send data to where the client has requested. You can have multiple outbounds and inbounds. The way inbound and outbound handles data is determined by different protocols (Socks, VMess, VLess, Freedom, etc.), and each protocol may have its own transport (TCP, mKcp, WebSocket, etc.).</p>
<p>VMess is an original and the most widely used protocol, developed by V2ray specifically for passing the deep packet inspection imposed by the GFW. VLess is an updated version of it that does not require time synchronization but does not have the traffic encrypted. Here we are going to setup a basic proxy using VMess.</p>
<hr>
<p><em><strong>Server</strong></em><br>
Log into your server and set the time if it's not what you have on the client.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">date -s 'year-month-day hour:minute:second'
</code></pre>
<p>It would be the easiest to install V2ray via their script.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">wget https://install.direct/go.sh
bash go.sh
</code></pre>
<p>After the installation is finished, we can proceed to edit the config file. It is included as part of the installation script, named <code>config.json</code>. It should be edited like this:</p>
<pre><code class="language-json">{
  &quot;log&quot;: {
      &quot;access&quot;: &quot;/var/log/v2ray/access.log&quot;,
      &quot;error&quot;: &quot;/var/log/v2ray/error.log&quot;,
      &quot;loglevel&quot;: &quot;info&quot;
  },
  &quot;inbounds&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;port&quot;: [port number],
      &quot;protocol&quot;: &quot;vmess&quot;,   
      &quot;settings&quot;: {
        &quot;clients&quot;: [
          {
            &quot;id&quot;: &quot;[your uuid]&quot;,
            &quot;alterId&quot;: [your alterid]
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  ],
  &quot;outbounds&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;protocol&quot;: &quot;freedom&quot;,
      &quot;settings&quot;: {}
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre>
<p><code>inbounds vmess port</code>: the listening port on the server<br>
<code>id</code>: the main id of the user. you can generate one <a href="https://www.uuidgenerator.net/">here</a><br>
<code>alterid</code>: used to pass the inspection. can be anywhere between 0 to the largest number your server can support<br>
<code>freedom</code>: passes all TCP or UDP connection to their destinations</p>
<p>Now start the service.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">systemctl start v2ray.service
</code></pre>
<p>If you have a firewall enabled, make sure to open the listening port. I am using ufw here.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">ufw allow [port number]/tcp
ufw allow [port number]/udp
</code></pre>
<p><em><strong>Linux Client</strong></em><br>
Find your system's architecture <a href="https://github.com/v2fly/v2ray-core/releases/tag/v4.37.3">here</a>. Download and extract it. Now find the <code>config.json</code> file and write it like this.</p>
<pre><code class="language-json">{
  &quot;log&quot;:{
   &quot;loglevel&quot;: &quot;info&quot;,
   &quot;access&quot;: &quot;/var/log/v2ray/access.log&quot;,
   &quot;error&quot;: &quot;/var/log/v2ray/error.log&quot;
  },
  &quot;inbounds&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;port&quot;: [port number],
      &quot;protocol&quot;: &quot;socks&quot;,
      &quot;sniffing&quot;: {
        &quot;enabled&quot;: true,
        &quot;destOverride&quot;: [&quot;http&quot;, &quot;tls&quot;]
      },
      &quot;settings&quot;: {
        &quot;auth&quot;: &quot;noauth&quot;  
      }
    },
    {
      &quot;port&quot;: [port number],
      &quot;protocol&quot;: &quot;http&quot;,
      &quot;sniffing&quot;: {
          &quot;enabled&quot;: true,
          &quot;destOverride&quot;: [&quot;http&quot;, &quot;tls&quot;]
        }
     }
  ],
  &quot;outbounds&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;protocol&quot;: &quot;vmess&quot;,
      &quot;settings&quot;: {
        &quot;vnext&quot;: [
          {
            &quot;address&quot;: &quot;[server's ip address]&quot;,
            &quot;port&quot;: [port number],  
            &quot;users&quot;: [
              {
                &quot;id&quot;: &quot;[your uuid]&quot;,  //need to be the same as the server config
                &quot;alterId&quot;: [your alterid], //need to be the same as the server config
                &quot;security&quot;: &quot;auto&quot;
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      &quot;mux&quot;: {&quot;enabled&quot;: true}
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre>
<p><code>inbounds socks port</code>: the listening port on your client for Socks protocol<br>
<code>sniffing</code>: content sniffing, can be used for solving DNS spoofing and setting rules for domains<br>
<code>noauth</code>: anonymous authentication<br>
<code>inbounds http port</code>: the listening port on your client for HTTP protocol<br>
<code>outbounds vmess port</code>: the listening port on your server<br>
<code>security</code>: can be <code>aes-128-gcm</code> for PC use, <code>chacha20-poly1305</code> for phone use, or <code>auto</code> for automatic detection<br>
<code>mux</code>: designed to reduce TCP handshake latency by using one physical TCP connections for multiple virtual TCP connections. might not be needed</p>
<p>To allow v2ray to autostart, you could add a systemd entry to the <code>/etc/systemd/system</code> folder. Make sure the config file and the executable file are in the same folder.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">[Unit]
Description=v2ray
After=network.target

[Service]
ExecStart=/path/to/v2ray

[Install]
WantedBy=multi-user.target
</code></pre>
<p>Start it and enable it.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">systemctl start v2ray.service
systemctl enable v2ray.service
</code></pre>
<p>If it can't be started, you might need to create the log files manually.</p>
<p><em><strong>Windows Client</strong></em><br>
Find your system's architecture <a href="https://github.com/v2fly/v2ray-core/releases/tag/v4.37.3">here</a>. Download and extract it. The config file should be the same as what I wrote above for linux and the only change you need to make is to delete the <code>log</code> sector because windows doesn't support it.</p>
<p>To autostart, create a .vbs file. Same thing here, make sure the config file and the exe file are in the same folder.</p>
<pre><code>Dim WinScriptHost
Set WinScriptHost = CreateObject(&quot;WScript.Shell&quot;)
WinScriptHost.Run Chr(34) &amp; &quot;path\to\v2ray.exe&quot; &amp; Chr(34), 0
Set WinScriptHost = Nothing
</code></pre>
<p>Create a shortcut of it and add it to the <code>shell:startup</code> folder.</p>
<hr>
<p>I also tried the WebSocket+TLS+Web+CDN combo, but somehow it didn't work. It might be some problem related to Cloudflare that I am too <del>dumb</del> lazy to figure out. The server is working fine, but the access log at the client is dumping on me tons of ambiguous errors. But if I do find the solution, I might update this later.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Overview of IPFS: Usage, Explanation, and Thoughts]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post/an-overview-of-ipfs-usage-explanation-and-history/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post/an-overview-of-ipfs-usage-explanation-and-history/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-03-18T14:21:22.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Until now, the World Wide Web relies on HTTP to transfer data and establish communication across the web. But in 2015, an American guy named Juan Benet created a new protocol called IPFS, or you might like its sci-fi sounding name better, <em>&quot;InterPlanetary File System&quot;</em>, to compete with HTTP. Instead of the classic server-client approach, IPFS decides to go with peer-to-peer, which should sound familiar if you know BitTorrent. <strong>To summarize it in a short sentence, IPFS is a peer-to-peer file sharing system that claims to be faster, safer, and more open.</strong></p>
<p>The goal of IPFS is to provide a better alternative for HTTP and ultimately, to replace HTTP. This sounds extremely ambitious, and that's why it interests me. However, after tried it for a little while, I have to say that IPFS is still too immature compared to HTTP, considering that the later one has dominated the web (to be more precise, it started the web) since its creation in the 90s and has evolved a lot after that. IPFS is a promising and somehow a little revolutionary project, but it still needs time to develop.</p>
<hr>
<p>First, let's take a look at how to use IPFS. In order to use IPFS, there are some basic concepts one needs to know:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Every file on the IPFS network has a unique hash, known as CID</strong>, that resembles a location address and we can use the hash to point to a specific file.</li>
<li><strong>IPFS is decentralized, which makes it function like a CDN</strong>. Files are being kept multiple backups so even if the node who originally published the specific file is down, the requested file can still be retrieved from other nodes. This process ensures speed and availability of most files.</li>
<li><strong>IPFS is a self-certifying file system (SFS)</strong>, which means that o special permission is needed for data exchange.</li>
<li><strong>The content on IPFS is not permanent unless it is pinned</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>###How to Retrieve Content<br>
There are currently four ways to retrieve content from IPFS: public gateway, local gateway, get/cat command, and Integrated IPFS in Brave browser.</p>
<p>####Public Gateway<br>
Protocol Labs maintains a <a href="https://ipfs.github.io/public-gateway-checker/">list of public gateways</a> that allows users to view the content of files on the  IPFS network without installing IPFS on their local machines.</p>
<p>To use it, choose an online gateway and follow the syntax here:<br>
<code>&lt;gateway address&gt;/ipfs/&lt;hash&gt;</code></p>
<p>For example, here is what you will type in your browser to access a copy of the Turkish wikipedia:<br>
<code>ipfs.io/ipfs/QmT5NvUtoM5nWFfrQdVrFtvGfKFmG7AHE8P34isapyhCxX/</code></p>
<p>####Local Gateway<br>
Download IPFS-Desktop from <a href="https://github.com/ipfs-shipyard/ipfs-desktop/releases/tag/v0.14.0">here</a> or use the Go implementation of IPFS by following this <a href="https://docs.ipfs.io/install/command-line/">guide</a> if you are on a remote server or just think GUI is bloated.</p>
<p>Initialize the repository:<br>
<code>ipfs init</code></p>
<p>Take the node online:<br>
<code>ipfs daemon</code><br>
<em>(or use a service manager if on Unix systems)</em></p>
<p>Now you can access content by typing this in your browser:<br>
<code>127.0.0.1:8080/ipfs/&lt;hash&gt;</code></p>
<p>The port can be specified in the config file.</p>
<p>####get/cat Command<br>
Make sure you have installed IPFS-Desktop or go-ipfs and the daemon is started.</p>
<p>The ipfs cat command is similar to the cat command on Unix systems and it reads content from the IPFS network.<br>
<code>ipfs cat &lt;hash&gt;</code></p>
<p>Alternatively, you can use the get command to download the content.<br>
<code>ipfs get &lt;hash&gt;</code></p>
<p>If nothing returns, it is possible that none of the peers you are connected to holds a copy of the file you requested. To check if any peer has the file, run:<br>
<code>ipfs dht findprovs &lt;hash&gt;</code></p>
<p>You cannot request a file from a specific peer because there is no point in doing this. All the files that share the same hash contain the identical content.</p>
<p>####Integrated IPFS in Brave Browser<br>
Brave anounced their support of IPFS in January this year. You can type this in Brave browser to access content:<br>
<code>ipfs://&lt;hash&gt;</code></p>
<p>Be aware that by default, Brave uses public gateways to load the requested content. Brave will suggest you to enable IPFS local daemon support if you are visiting through a public gateway, and by clicking &quot;Enable IPFS&quot;, Brave will automatically download go-ipfs and route all IPFS traffic through your local gateway.</p>
<p>###How To Add Content<br>
Download IPFS-Desktop <a href="https://github.com/ipfs-shipyard/ipfs-desktop/releases/tag/v0.14.0">here</a> or follow this <a href="https://docs.ipfs.io/install/command-line/">guide</a> to install go-ipfs if you have not already done so. Now you are able to upload file from the desktop app, webUI, or directly from the command line. I guess <a href="https://pinata.cloud/">pinata</a> will also work, but I have never tried it.</p>
<p>####Desktop App &amp; GUI<br>
Open the app or access the webUI by typing this in your browser:<br>
<code>127.0.0.1:5001/webui</code><br>
<em>(you need to start the daemon first in order to access the webUI and the port can be speficied in the config file or through 'settings')</em></p>
<p>Click import and pin it if needed.</p>
<p>####Command line<br>
To add a file, run:<br>
<code>ipfs add path/to/file</code></p>
<p>Add -r to add a directory.<br>
<code>ipfs add -r path/to/directory</code><br>
<em>(Record the hash because you need it later to access your file. )</em></p>
<p>To pin the file, run:<br>
<code>ipfs pin add &lt;hash&gt;</code></p>
<p>Or add -r for directory.</p>
<p>Other basic commands are explained by <code>ipfs -h</code>. Please use them for reference.</p>
<hr>
<p>Now we can get deeper into the structure of IPFS.</p>
<p>###DHT<br>
<strong>DHT, or distributed hash table, is a data structure used by IPFS that stores information as key pairs</strong>. Relying on DHT's decentralization, IPFS is able to function even if some nodes do down.</p>
<p>###Merkle DAG<br>
IPFS uses Merkle DAG as its data structure. According to the <a href="https://docs.ipfs.io/concepts/merkle-dag/#further-resources">official documentation of IPFS</a>, <em>&quot;A Merkle DAG is a DAG where each node has an identifier, and this is the result of hashing the node's contents — any opaque payload carried by the node and the list of identifiers of its children — using a cryptographic hash function like SHA256. &quot;</em> Merkle DAG resembles a &quot;reversed tree&quot; in which grows from leaves to branch. In order to link children's identifiers to the parents, children's identifiers must be calculated first.</p>
<p>If you recall how I mentioned why request to a specific peer is unnecessary, here is a more detailed explanation: <strong>all nodes are given a unique CID (identifier or can just be called hash) to be identified from the network and the CID is linked to all its descendants</strong>. Copies of the requested objects with that CID from all peers are identical because they share the same DAG. If a change is made in one node, its identifier would alter which also causes its ascendants to alter correspondingly. This process creates a new DAG that cannot be retrieved using the original identifier.</p>
<p>###IPFS Objects<br>
An IPFS object is a structure that contains two fields, which can be visualized as follows</p>
<ul>
<li>data: unstructured binary data &lt; 256kb</li>
<li>Links: links that point to other IPFS objects
<ul>
<li>Name: the name of the link</li>
<li>Hash: the hash of the linked object</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>You can see the structure of any object by running <code>ipfs object get &lt;hash&gt;</code>.</p>
<p>If the object is smaller than 256kb, the <em>links</em> section will be empty because there is no other sectors to point to. But if the object is larger than 256kb, it is going to be further divided into sectors that are smaller than 256kb and the <em>name</em> section will be empty. Each sector will get an unique hash and the final hash for the file will be calculated after combining all the sector hashes into one group. This works inversely when retrieving files. When an user requests a file from the network by hash, the sector hashes specified by that file hash will be searched and downloaded from the node that holds it. After that, they will be arranged in the correct order and will be assembled locally.</p>
<p>IPFS also works like Git that it supports versions. The commit object will have one or more links that point to previous commits, and one object link that points to the DAG for that commit.</p>
<hr>
<p>Even though the concept of a decentralized file system and content addressing sounds really attractive, IPFS still remains a toy for those tech enthusiasts after 6 years. <strong>To me IPFS is a powerful tool, yet also powerless due to its developers' ambition to overthrow the traditional structure of web</strong>. It would be better for it to focus on a specific field, gain more active users, and then consider the next step if its ultimate goal is to compete in a monopolized market. Despite IPFS's attempts at conquering every corner of the web that involves static content, better, easier, and more stable alternatives have all already existed which makes the invention of IPFS somehow purposeless. This is getting even more difficult regarding dynamic content.</p>
<p>Common usages of IPFS involve static website hosting, file backup, file sharing, etc. As I stated previously, IPFS is capable at completing many tasks, but excel at none of them. The speed of IPFS is also concerning (or maybe I should put the blame on my computer rather tha IPFS) compared to other data exchanging services. We are now already at a shortage of nodes as its user base remains small.</p>
<p>One common misconception for IPFS that tempts some users to try it is that it is private, but in fact it is not if you are running it on open network without assist from file encryption, VPN/Tor, or establishment of a private IPFS network.</p>
<p>I would not argue that IPFS is completely useless, as its performance in the 2017 Catalan independence referendum has proved that <strong>IPFS can be used to combat censorship under an authoritarian government that obtains massive amount of resources to block the country's access to the free world</strong>. In 2017, the Spanish government has blocked every website about the referendum to restrain the spread of information. Soon the Catalan government moved the website to IPFS and despite the Spanish government's multiple attempts at blocking all public gateways by brutal force, new nodes always arise as people started to maintain their own nodes. Again, IPFS is not private, so many citizens who published information on the referendum were arrested by the Spanish government as a result.</p>
<p>You could argue that there are better alternatives for secure information sharing, like how Hong Kong protesters used the Telegram channel to broadcast news during the 2020 Anti-Extradition Law Amendment Bill Movement. The main, and allow me to say this, the only advantage of IPFS is decentralization. It does not matter how powerful and resourceful a government is, as long as there is internet, information can be spread. The only concern right now is how to find an accessible gateway without pinging every known gateway in a country where IPFS is &quot;censored&quot;.</p>
<p>In fact, IPFS is not the only project who has introduced the idea of decentralized file sharing. An anonymous Chinese blogger famous for his/her criticism of the Chinese government and comprehensive privacy guides titled &quot;Programthink&quot; has used BitTorrent Sync, a decentralized file synchronization tool, to spread banned books in mainland China.</p>
<p>This is just a summary of how IPFS operates and my brief thought on it. I am looking forward to seeing more creative or practical usage of it, but right now I find no particular reason to use it. However, I would be really interested to see if the implementation of IPFS would be successful in China, as I have not seen any wide usage of it even among those who are able to pass through GFW. Yet in other countries that are not intensely censored, the probability of IPFS overtaking older protocols seems low, as IPFS aims to subvert the base system of the web.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Peace & Love", Self-censorship, and the Future of Social Media]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post/peace-and-love-self-censorship-and-the-future-of-social-media/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post/peace-and-love-self-censorship-and-the-future-of-social-media/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-03-05T09:07:43.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have been following up on news recently (well, maybe not that recent), you might have already heard an overwhelming amount of reports that concerns censorship involving Trump ban; removal of Parler, a right wing social media platform that gains reputation during Capitol riots; removal of &quot;<em>When Harry became Sally</em>&quot;, a controversial book criticized for its transphobia; and the most recent one is the removal of Dr. Seuss's six books that &quot;portray people in ways that are hurtful and wrong&quot; according to Dr. Seuss Enterprises.</p>
<p>Relying on its tremendous amount of users across the globe, Big Tech is deprecated for its monopolization of tech industry and deprivation of free speech. After realizing this ugly truth of modern social media, many users have decided to move to alternative self-hosted platforms such as mastodon and therefore have learned the concept of decentralization.</p>
<p>I am indeed in opposition with Big Tech, who demonstrates its manipulation of voices through censorship of different views. However, I can't quite agree with the opinion that a fully decentralized social media will create a censorship-free zone for people to utilize their freedom of speech. Yes, decentralization is helping, but not hundred percent. Big Tech is a problem, but it might be too late to eliminate them and to restore a platform where all these account suspension, shadow ban, cancel culture etc. are merely words that sound like a bad meme. This is what I want to talk about here: <strong>how the &quot;Peace &amp; Love&quot; propaganda encourages self-censorship and why I am pessimistic about the future of social media.</strong></p>
<hr>
<p>It might be my bias, but when I think of propaganda, the only thing that comes into my mind is the government. Even if the media and tech companies are the ones that spread the propaganda, I still consider them a puppet of the government who serve as the messenger rather than the director. It has never occurred to me that <strong>corporations can function entirely independent of the government while developing into a certain size that allows it to acquire supremacy in which resembles a second government</strong> as you can see from the Trump ban incident. Due to people's innate distrust of the government, the potential risk involved in those corporations could be more harmful and harder to spot in most situations. In addition to that, the biased information they hope their audiences to believe does not really echo the &quot;definition of propaganda&quot; from your education on Nazi propaganda in your middle school history class. This strange type of propaganda from corporations, who are mostly controlled by the liberals or tend to gain benefits from promoting liberal ideologies, is what I would like to call &quot;Peace &amp; Love&quot;.</p>
<p>I can't find a combination of words that summarizes liberal ideologies as well as peace and love, considering that social equality, egalitarianism, and justice are the three main themes of it. liberals in the US have been active in resistance against racism, sexism, homophobia, etc. and tend to encourage more aggressive immigration policies and to support &quot;minority communities&quot; such as the LGBTQ group. At first glance, <strong>it is hard to notice any incoherence in liberals' ideologies, since they resonate the preamble of American Constitution in which all men are created equal and depict an utopian society free of hate or conflicts.</strong> But here the question comes: how do we define the boundary between hate and regular expression? We have been told to uphold the &quot;Peace &amp; Love&quot; ideology, but explanations liberals provide us are either ambiguous paraphrases that link back to their statements or contradictions that eventually lead to more confusion.</p>
<p>Here I will provide my own brief definition of &quot;hate&quot;: clear hostility displayed toward a certain group or individual. The keywords here are &quot;hostility&quot; and &quot;displayed&quot;. Stereotype is not hate, neither are &quot;offensive sounding&quot; jokes or thoughts inside your head. I do understand that everyone has their own definition of hate, and everyone has their own trigger words. <strong>What I do not understand is that how everything can be labeled as &quot;hate&quot; nowadays and how liberals use &quot;justice for all&quot; as an excuse to censor the entire internet</strong>.</p>
<p>The invention of &quot;cultural appropriation&quot; is a perfect example for my point. If you don't know this word, it means &quot;<em>the adoption of an element or elements of one culture or identity by members of another culture or identity that can be controversial when members of a dominant culture appropriate from disadvantaged minority cultures</em>&quot; according to wikipedia. It's quite lengthy, but the basic meaning I have grepped is that using elements from other culture can be offending sometimes if they don't represent their original meanings. For example, a white girl, a member of &quot;dominant culture&quot;, can be accused of cultural appropriation for wearing kimono because she doesn't display enough knowledge of Japanese culture. I think that the concept of cultural appropriation is intended to increase respect for cultures one is not familiar with, but in practice, it is the sudo word for completely inaccurate accusation of discrimination and somehow accomplishes the inverse of its original purpose.</p>
<p>As a result of liberal' attempt to serve justice for &quot;repressive minority groups&quot;, majority groups become the new target of discrimination. It is almost a trend now for mainstream media to ask for white people's apology for their skin color, or to ask &quot;cisgender&quot; (a person whose sense of personal identity and gender corresponds with their birth sex) to use pronouns.</p>
<p><strong>The illusion of an ideal society, the fanatical obsession of &quot;equality&quot;, and a distorted understanding of mutual respect set the standards for &quot;Peace &amp; Love&quot; ideologies and further developed into liberal propaganda</strong>. Just as you can see from Amazon's removal of &quot;<em>When Harry became Sally</em>&quot;, corporations are the ones who determine what the mass can believe, and the disciples of &quot;Peace &amp; Love&quot; idodelogy are the ones who will support it from the botttom of their hearts.</p>
<hr>
<p>By the help from Big Tech, &quot;Peace $ Love&quot; ideology dominates mainstream social media nowadays. Any opposite opinion is likely to be reported for &quot;violating the company's policy&quot;. But would social media improve off Big Techs' hands? Only if the mass stops voluntary self-regulation of their own views.</p>
<p>According to <a href='https://poseidon01.ssrn.com/delivery.php?ID=301002120071064114068121064110111105032027023067011038006026013072078073068029111101021018111115103010043005029093105124099092098074087007053118099114012100001077091026021066068127020095069086069004011105003030026000090029010104094095006006093112069089&EXT=pdf&INDEX=TRUE' style='color: #756e66'>the Washington University in St. Louis study</a>, &quot;<em>self-censorship is more common among women (43%) than among men (37%); more common in metro areas (42%) than in non-metro areas (33%); more common among those with only a high school degree (34%) and at least some college (45%) than among those with no high school diploma (27%)</em>&quot;. This is a shocking set of data as almost half of the US regularly censors oneself, while those who possess high levels of education are even more likely to do so. The study credits to &quot;growing affective political polarization&quot; for this abnormal phenomenon, and I can quite agree with that.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Because people so dislike each other and detest each other’s views and values, they perceive a great cost associated with sharing their opinions publicly, for little or no reward.Therefore, they keep their mouths shut and refrain from expressing their true views.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I did some research but couldn't find a good demographic profile for liberals in the US. Liberals make up the largest share of Democratic voters so I think it is safe to use the demographic of democrats to find correlations between political belief and the likability to self-censor. According to this <a href='https://www.debt.org/faqs/americans-in-debt/economic-demographics-democrats/' style='color: #756e66'>post</a>, &quot;<em>democrats dominate the more populated, urban centers (60%); attract more women (37%) than men (27%); are more likely to have post-graduate degrees or no high school diploma</em>&quot;. It is interesting to see how it almost overlaps the data from the self-censorship study, as both data sets mention a higher percentage of those who are female, reside in urban areas, and have received high education.</p>
<p>At this point, we can say that <strong>liberal ideologies tend to encourage more self-censorship due to its promotion of social justice, in which one is likely to keep silent on sensitive topics in order to avoid potential offense to their opponent</strong>. The &quot;Peace &amp; Love&quot; propaganda influences a majority of its believers to not only be cautious when expressing their views under censorship from other entities, but also when no restriction is present. To dodge that &quot;hate&quot; label and not to be ostracized from the group, many have decided to shut their mouth. People can never be free if they deny to accept their own opinions and instead follow the rules for respect obediently just to not accidentally shout out the trigger words. Linking back to what I have said earlier, <strong>decentralization liberates us from Big Tech, but the only one who can liberate us from our mind is ourselves</strong>. It's a sad truth to say that a lot of people have been locked up by &quot;Peace &amp; Love&quot; ideology that they are unable to say, or even further, unable to see or listen.</p>
<hr>
<p>Thanks to the development of internet, people are able to publish their ideas and interact with people from the globe on social media. But the concerning thing of social media, apart from censorship from corporations who own the platform, is self-censorship I have mentioned. Despite freedom from Big Tech, many users of alternative social media still tend to limit what they can see or say. The most famous one among them is known as the fediverse, &quot;<em>an ensemble of federated servers that are used for web publishing and file hosting, but which, while independently hosted, can communicate with each other</em>&quot;, according to wikipedia. It is a decentralized social media in simpler words.</p>
<p>While some people have taken the advantage from fediverse to freely express their opinions, a group of people did not appreciate this opportunity and turned fediverse into fedisolo by starting fediblock, a list of instances they recommend other instance administrators to block due to reasons like spam, hate speech, or without any reason. There is clearly no third party involved in the creation of fediblock and it is a self-initiated movement to bring censorship to fediverse. But since administrators cannot directly ban accounts from other instances, the only thing they can accomplish to show their disapproval of different opinions is to call everyone a &quot;Nazi&quot;. I used to promote fediverse as a place free of censorship to my Twitter friends until one person wrote to me a 800 word sophisticated response on why I am an asshole who takes no responsibility in my words. He argues that freedom of speech is still at the hands of administrators, therefore I have no right to say such thing. He got a point, even though his attitude is terrible.</p>
<p>I have said that I am pessimistic about the future of social media even if it is decentralized, and I think it is better to classify the uniqueness of social media before I explain my reason on feeling this way. <strong>A social media is a platform for different people to exchange ideas and is intended to facilitate this process by its &quot;real time interaction&quot; feature, while other internet platforms might not necessitate interaction with one another</strong>. To simplify it even further, <strong>we are dependent on each other when it comes to censorship in social media while having the option to be independent on other internet platforms</strong>. You can argue that self-hosted instance would be a solution to the dependency problem for the fediverse example, but do realize that other instances still have the power to block you, which is the equivalent for alienation. The point of social media is to establish relationship with each other, and the presence of censorship prevents this to happen. This is the unspoken rule of any decentralized social media: <strong>self censor or get out</strong>, as we can see from fediverse that a majority of pleroma instances are blocked by mastodon instances for various reasons.</p>
<p>It is not possible for social media to regain freedom of speech unless its users realize the importance of free speech and stop self-censoring. <strong>As long as people are still using &quot;*&quot; to replace words they find &quot;inappropriate&quot;, blocking everyone apart from those who share their opinions, consider everything as hate speech, or losing their mind on politically incorrect yet harmless jokes, we will never have a free social media regardless of decentralization</strong>. Otherwise, we will all be an isolated island from each other and nothing of this reflects the definition of social media or foreseeing an optimistic future. The impact &quot;Love &amp; Peace&quot; ideologies have done on people is irreversible.</p>
<p>Well, in the end, I still hope one day we can have a large-scale social media free of any form of censorship. See you freedom, someday, somewhere!</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post !!!]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post/first-post/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.tapiocanation.xyz/post/first-post/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-02-22T03:10:13.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So as you can see, I have decided to give gridea a try since it looks easy to configure and use. It''s a great static blog writing client for lazy people and non-techies. They should really promote themselves more instead of only focusing on Chinese users but somehow they didn't even manage to add English translation to their website.</p>
<p>Btw they support linux.</p>
<p>I guess I will use it for few more weeks and decide if I like it or not.</p>
<p>This blog does not have any specific theme. I will try to update it at least once a month or even better, once a week. It would be good if you are willing to provide any feedback as it might encourage me to continue writing. But if you don't care, that's okay too. Just contact me by ways listed <a href='https://tapiocanation.xyz/contact.html' style='color: #756e66'>here</a>. Comment system willl not be implemented because I dislike them on blogs.</p>
<p>Enjoy.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>